A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 11775-13948 FA739E
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Developing partnerships for forest stewardship and rural economic development: Synthesis of a conference of the National Network of Forest Practitioners: Washington, D.C., January 19-20 (Reports 013531), 1994 (Box 716, Reel R-9295)
  Draft of paper concerning a conference held jointly by the Forest Trust and the Forest Policy Center on natural resource development, rural assistance, and strengthening local and federal partnerships toward sustainable land stewardship.
  Developing Partnerships for Forest Stewardship and Rural Economic Development, Washington, D.C., January 19-20, 1994
  Rural development -- United States; Non-governmental organizations -- United States; Timber -- Harvesting -- United States; Forest and forestry -- Economic aspects -- United States; National Network of Forest Practioners (U.S.)
- Proyecto Centro Ecologico Intercultural del Cahuinari una Estrategia para la Consolidacion de los Territorios Indigenas (Reports 013532), 1987 (Box 716, Reel R-9295)
  Report on the Foundation's work in Colombia in the promotion of alternative methods for the use and management of threatened ecosystems in such a way that social needs are satisfied while preserving the biological diversity and natural resources available[…]Photostat copy of report prepared almost entirely in Spanish. Purpose statement and programs and works descriptions are in English, as well as information on chairmen and funding found on the back page.
  08800635
  Rain forests -- Management -- Colombia; Biodiversity conservation -- Colombia; Environmental responsibility -- Colombia; Centro Ecologico Intercultural del Cahuinari
- La Tortuga charapa (Podocnemis expansa), en el Bajo Rio Caqueta, Amazonas, Colombia, Abril (Reports 013533), 1995 (Box 716, Reel R-9295)
  Report on the conversation efforts of the charapa turtles (tortuga charapa) in the lower Caqueta (Japura) river in Colombia.[…]Report is written entirely in Spanish.
  Turtles -- Colombia; Wildlife conservation -- Colombia; Sea turtles -- Colombia; Ford Foundation; Cultural Survival Inc.; Zoological Society of San Diego; Vida Silvestre; Fondo Colombiano de Investigaciones Científicas y Proyectos Especiales Francisco José de Caldas
- Philippine Agrarian Reform Foundation for National Development (PARFUND): outline and overview for series of PO and NGO regional consultations, 30 April to 30 (Reports 013534), 1994 (Box 716, Reel R-9295)
  Listing of PO and NGO regional consultations that took place throughout the Philippines in 1994 on the issue of forming NGO and PO partnerships to tackle agrarian reform and rural development.
  09351435
  Land reform -- Philippines -- Congresses; Rural development -- Social aspects -- Philippines -- Congresses; Non-governmental organizations -- Philippines -- Congresses; Philippine Agrarian Reform Foundation for National Development; Ford Foundation
- Mixtec migrant farmworkers in California agriculture: A dialogue among Mixtec leaders, researchers, and farm labor advocates, Jan. (Reports 013535), 1992 (Box 716, Reel R-9295)
  Working paper on the migration of Mixtec Indians from the state of Oaxaca, Mexico. Paper examines the working and living conditions of the migrant farm workers, the effect of migrant workers on farm labor markets in general, and suggests improvements to t[…]Working group on farm labor and rural poverty, Working Paper #9 (January 1992).
  08900633
  Alien labor -- California; Agricultural laborers -- California; Mixtec Indians -- California; Zabin, Carol; California Institute for Rural Studies, Inc.; University of California at San Diego. Center for U.S. Mexican Studies
- Mixtec migrants in California agriculture: A new cycle of poverty: Research report presented to the Aspen Institute Rural Economic Policy Program: 4th draft (Reports 013536), 1992 (Box 716, Reel R-9295)
  Report on migrant farm workers from the state of Oaxaca, Mexico living and working in California. The report gives a history of Mixtec Indians and provides analysis of migrant farmer's effects on the farm labor market in the United States.[…]Fourth Draft -- July 1992
  Migrant agricultural laborers -- California; Mixtec Indians -- Emigration and immigration -- California; Agricultural labors -- California; California Institute for Rural Studies, Inc.; University of California at San Diego. Center for U.S. Mexican Studies; Aspen Institute
- A survey of Oaxacan village networks in California agriculture draft, July 20 (Reports 013537), 1994 (Box 716, Reel R-9295)
  Survey of California regions were Mixtec Indians from Oaxaca have settled for agricultural labor employment, with detailed survey of towns/villages in Oaxaca where the migrant workers have migrated from, as well as details of locations within California w[…]Follow up report to Carol Zabin's, Mixtec in California Agriculture: A New Cycle of Poverty.
  Mixtec Indians -- California; Migrant agricultural laborers -- California; Migrant labor -- Legal status, laws, etc.; California Institute for Rural Studies; Aspen Institute. Rural Economic Policy Program; Ford Foundation. Rural Poverty and Resources
- Mixtec migrants in California agriculture: A new cycle of poverty: Research report presented to the Rural Economic Policy Program of the Aspen Institute and the Ford Foundation (Reports 013538), 1993 (Box 716, Reel R-9295)
  Final report on the status of Mixtec migrant agricultural laborers in California, with emphasis placed on living and working conditions, legal status of migrant workers, and the organization of the various communities in order to gain strength and protect
  Mixtec Indians -- California; Migrant labor -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Migrant agricultural laborers -- California; California Institute for Rural Studies; Ford Foundation. Rural Poverty and Resources; Aspen Institute. Rural Economic Policy Program
- Demand for labor, wages, and productivity in Mexican fruits and vegetables: Preliminary estimates and implications for NAFTA, Sept. (Reports 013539), 1992 (Box 716, Reel R-9295)
  Report is double-sided.
  Latin American Studies Association. National Meeting (Los Angeles, Calif.: 1992).
  Commodity exchanges -- Mexico; Produce trade -- Law and legislation -- Mexico; International trade -- Effect of wage differentials on; NAFTA Center (U.S.)
- Migracion Oaxaquena a los campos agricolas de California: Un dialogo: Conference proceedings draft, not for circulation 1990? (Reports 013540) (Box 716, Reel R-9295)
  Summary of conference proceedings on the organizational efforts of community activists, scholars, and Mixtec leaders on the issue of Oaxacan migrant farm workers in California.[…]Report is a summary of a one day workshop that was held on the issue of Mixtec migrant farm laborer with the aim of bringing scholars, farm labor advocates, union organizers and Mixtec leaders together to advance the organizational projects of the Mixtec
  Mixtec Indians -- California; Migrant agriculrural laborers -- California; Migrant labor -- Legal status, laws, etc.; California Institute for Rural Studies; Ford Foundation. Rural Poverty and Resources
- Anthropological perspectives on transnational communities in rural California 1990? (Reports 013541) (Box 716, Reel R-9295)
  An anthropological analysis of transnational communities, particularly of Mexican origin, living and working in rural California.
  California Institute for Rural Studies, Inc.
  Transnationalism -- California; Migrant labor -- California; Minorities -- Civil rights; Aliens -- United States -- Identification; University of California, Riverside. Dept. of Anthropology; University of California, Santa Cruz. Department of Community Studies; Ford Foundation. Rural Poverty and Resources; California Institute for Rural Studies, Inc.
- Report of Advisory Meeting on "Hopes on the Horizon: the Rise of the New Africa: 1955-1995" (Reports 013542), 1994 (Box 716, Reel R-9295)
  Advisory meeting summary on the production of the documentary on Africa, entitled "Hopes on the Horizon: The Rise of the New Africa: 1955-1995."[…]The information provided for the title seems to be gleaned from reviewing the documents -- there is no title page, authorship information, or specific dates for authority reference.
  09501481
  The Civil Rights Project, Inc.
  Documentary videos -- Africa; Human rights -- Africa; African Council on Communication Education; Ford Foundation. Africa and Middle East; Ford Foundation. Media, Arts and Culture; The Civil Rights Project, Inc.
- Papers and related documents from the Conference of African Research Institutes (Reports 013543), 1990 (Box 716, Reel R-9295)
  Collection of papers related to the Conference of African Research Institutes held in Algeria, March 24 - 25, 1990. The purpose of the conference was to discuss Africa's position on military disarmament.[…]Nine separate individually-authored papers are contained within this folder. Papers span sessions one through four of the conference.
  08900581
  Conference of African Research Institutes -- (1990: Algiers, Algeria)
  Disarmament; Arms control -- Congresses; United Nations Institute for Disarmament Research; Maʻhad al-Waṭanī lil-Dirāsāt al-Istirātījīyah al-Shāmilah (Algeria)
- Conference on communications and crises: The role of the media in the peaceful resolution of conflicts in Africa Final document, May 1992 / (Reports 013544) (Box 716, Reel R-9295)
  International conference, held in Africa in 1992, aimed at exploring the various ways of mobilizing the media and enhancing its role in crisis diffusion, conflict resolution and the strengthening of relations among African states and peoples (Preamble, pa
  Communications and Crisis: The Role of Media in the Peaceful Resolution of Conflicts in Africa (Lome, Togo, 1992)
  Conflict management -- Congresses; Press -- Congresses; Peaceful societies -- Africa; Regional Centre for Peace and Disarmament in Africa (United Nations); Ford Foundation. Africa and Middle East
- Collection of key issue papers and participants related to the experts' workshop on the research project entitled "Defining an Agenda for Peace and Progress in Africa", August 14-18, 1989, Lome, Togo (Reports 013545) (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  Workshop convened to discuss peaceful existence among African states.[…]Folder contains four separate documents, including the final agenda paper prepared by the workshop participants.
  Defining an Agenda for Peace and Progress in Africa (Lome, Tome: 1989)
  Peaceful societies -- Africa; Disarmament -- Africa; Conflict management -- Africa; Stockholm International Peace Research Institute; Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy; Paul H. Nitze School of Advanced International Studies
- Training agricultural scientists for Southern Africa: Southern African Development Coordination Conference (Reports 013546), 1985 (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  Report on the need for training agricultural scientists in Southern Africa, with appendices of several African universities and colleges that have agricultural departments.[…]Report submitted to the Ministry of Agriculture, Harare, Zimbabwe.
  08600175
  Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Africa, Southern; Universities and colleges -- Africa; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Africa, Southern; Faculdade de Ciencias Agarias; Botswana College of Agriculture; Lesotho Agricultural College; University of Malawi. Bunda College of Agriculture; Universidade Eduardo Mondlane; University of Swaziland; Sokoine University of Agriculture; University of Zambia
- Communities and consensus: An evaluation of the activities of the Nyae Nyae Farmers Cooperative and the Nyae Nyae Development Foundation in Northeastern Namibia, Nov. (Reports 013547), 1992 (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  Report and evaluation of the Nyae Nyae region of Nambia, with an analysis of farmers, agriculture, and water and land rights.
  09250771
  Land tenure -- Nambia; Water rights -- Nambia; Farmers -- Economic conditions -- Nambia; San (African people); Agriculture, Cooperative; Nyae Nyae Farmers' Co-operative; Nyae Nyae Development Foundation of Namibia
- Time to get cookin' in the south (or "If you can't stand the kitchen turn down the heat"): A report on MDC's October 1993 Conference on Development Strategies for Reducing Poverty in the South, Jan. (Reports 013548), 1994 (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  Report summary of a conference held with the aim of assisting local and regional organizations gain insight into approaches that can foster economic development and reduce poverty in the rural South (Preface, i).
  09200872
  Rural poor -- Southern United States; Housing -- Southern United States; Job creation -- Southern United States; Economic development projects -- Southern United States; MDC, Inc.; Ford Foundation. Rural Poverty and Resources; John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation; James C. Penny Foundation
- Resources to support activities in agriculture and natural resources in sub-Saharan Africa: Proposed analytical agenda with FY 1993 funding under the Policy, Analysis, Research, and Technical Support (PARTS) project, Jan. (Reports 013549) (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  Report presents a summary of the activities proposed to be undertaken in the area of agriculture and natural resources management in Africa over the FY 1993, 1994 (Summary, page 1).
  Natural resources -- Conservation -- Africa; Sustainable agriculture -- Africa; Food supply -- Africa; Environmental protection -- Government policy -- Africa; United States. Agency for International Development; United States. Agency for International Development. Bureau for Africa. Office of Analysis, Research, and Technical Support. Division of Food, Agriculture, and Resources Analysis; Ford Foundation. Rural Poverty and Resources
- Arab NGO Preparatory Meeting for the Fourth World Conference on Women: Cairo 1-3 (Reports 013550), 1994 (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  Prepatory meeting, held in Cairo in August 1995, for the 4th world conference on women.[…]Materials contain agenda items, and appendices for preparation of NGO participants attending the 4th World Conference on Women.
  09451074
  World Conference on Women -- (4th: 1995: Beijing, China)
  Women's rights -- Congresses; Non-governmental organizations -- Congresses; Women and peace -- Congresses; Women in development -- Congresses; Sex discrimination -- Congresses; United Nations. Economic and Social Council; Commission on the Status of Women; Ford Foundation
- The economics of dry season vegetable production in Nigeria, Feb. (Reports 013551), 1992 (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  Paper discusses and compares the costs and returns structures in the production of vegetables under the four irrigation systems, with an aim to compare profitability under the various systems and identify factors that enhance profitability (Abstract, page
  International Horticultural Congress (23rd: 1990: Florence, Italy)
  Vegetables -- Water requirements -- Africa; Agriculture -- On-farm research -- Africa; Agriculture -- Prices -- Africa; Irrigation farming -- Africa; University of Ibadan; Ford Foundation. Rural Poverty and Resources
- Crisis of irrigation development in West Africa 1986? (Reports 013552) (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  Paper examines the irrigation dilema in West Africa given the fact that the sub-region has abundant natural and human resources. Report recommends small irrigation projects, as well as government presence in irigation projects (Abstract, page 24).
  Irrigation farming -- Africa, West; Agriculture -- Africa, West; Rain and rainfall -- Periodicity -- Africa, West; University of Ibadan
- In Service to Democracy: Exploring the Nonprofit Sector: A conference hosted by John F. Kennedy School of Government, May 4 (Reports 013553), 1994 (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  09050780
  In Service to Democracy: Exploring the Nonprofit Sector (Cambridge, Mass.: 1994)
  Nonprofit organizations -- Law and legislation -- Congresses; Public policy (Canon law) -- Congresses; John F. Kennedy School of Government; Ford Foundation. Governance and Public Policy
- Workshop: Coping strategies of female-headed households: NGO Forum on Women, Beijing (Reports 013554), 1995 (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  Summary documents of a workshop discussing female heads of household given at the NGO Forum on Women in Beijing, 1995.
  09550973
  NGO Forum on Women, Beijing '95
  Heads of households; Household surveys; Women, Arab; Muslim women -- Conduct of life; Muslim women -- Education; ENDA. Inter Arabe; Ben Hamida, Essma
- International Conference of Indigenous Peoples on the Environment and Development (Reports 013555), 1992 (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  Conference aimed at tackling global environmental issues with the assistance of indigenous peoples.[…]Documents include budget projections for the conference as well as establishing offices thoughout the United States and abroad.
  09100473
  International Conference of Indigenous Peoples on the Environment and Development (1992: Brazil)
  Indigenous peoples -- Ecology -- Congresses; Indigenous peoples -- International cooperation -- Congresses; Environmental protection -- Congresses; Ahiaba, Beatriz; Center of Our Common Future. International Indigenous Commission.
- International assistance to South African exiles and refugees: A reference guide, Jan. (Reports 013556), 1990 (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  08700473
  South African Information Exchange working paper;no. 8
  Political refugees -- Services for -- South Africa; South Africans -- Foreign countries -- Services for -- Directories; Institute of International Education (New York, N.Y.); Institute of International Education, Inc.
- Some sources for tertiary-level bursaries within South Africa: A matrix, Jan. (Reports 013557), 1990 (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  South African Information Exchange working paper;no. 9
  Scholarships -- South Africa -- Directories; Institute of International Education (New York, N.Y.); Institute of International Education, Inc.
- The career development fellowship program: Adapting a highly effective initiative to changing needs 1991? (Reports 013558) (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  Summary of career development program that offers teaching and practical learning experiences in the United States to South Africans at mid-career (Introduction, page 1).[…]Draft is hand-written on first page.
  Career development -- South Africa; Education, Higher -- South Africa; Mentoring in the professions -- South Africa; Students, Foreign -- South Africa; Career Development Fellowship Program
- Papers from the Workshop on Conflict Resolution, Crisis Prevention, Management and Confidence Building, held in Yaounde, Cameroon in June of 1991. (Reports 013559) (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  Workshop on Conflict Resolution, Crisis Prevention, Management and Confidence Building (1991: Yaounde, Cameroon)
  Security, International; Peacekeeping forces; United Nations
- Productivity under uncertain irrigation: a look at tank irrigated rice cultivation in Andhra Pradesh (Reports 013560), 1985 (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  08300774
  Rice -- Irrigation -- India -- Andhra Pradesh
- The cursed questions: research report (Reports 013561), 1993 (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  09051073
  Washington Media Associates, Inc.
  Research for a documentary film on U.S. rural poverty.
  Political science -- Russia (Federation); Washington Media Associates; Washington Media Associates, Inc.; Washington Media Associates, Inc.
- Priorities and strategies for the work of rural social scientists (Reports 013562), 1988 (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  Report from Phase II Workshop/Conference of the Social Science Agricultural Agenda Project, March 13-18, 1988.
  08750576
  Support to broaden participation in the project's series of workshops and conferences planned for 1987-89.
  Social scientists -- Congresses; Social scientists -- Developing countries; Social science -- Research -- Developing countries; Rural development; Pakistan Agricultural Research Council. Social Science Division; Michigan State University. Department of Agricultural Economics; Ford Foundation. Rural Poverty and Resources; Michigan State University
- Foro: Desarrollo comercial en el sector social de pequenos productores: Retos y alternativas (Reports 013563), 1996 (Box 717, Reel R-9295)
  Report on small organizations in regions of Mexico producing various commodities for export. Report examines economic and social aspects of commercial production in Mexico, paying special attention to fair trade practices.[…]Report is written entirely in Spanish.
  09551080
  Artisans -- Mexico; Agriculture -- Mexico; Export duties on coffee -- Mexico; Anti-globalization movement -- Mexico; Asociacion Mexicana de Arte and Cultura Popular; Ford Foundation. Latin America and Caribbean
- The state of world rural poverty: Background reading, Rural Poverty and Resources Program: Board of Trustees Meeting, September 1994. (Reports 013564) (Box 718, Reel R-9295)
  Rural poor
- Ford Foundation initiative on sustaining peace in Central America: Notes from the Mexico City Office, September 20 (Reports 013565), 1995 (Box 718, Reel R-9295)
  Collection of papers from the Mexico and Central America Field Office. Papers pertain to specific grants and grantees in Mexico and Latin America in areas of media, electronic information services, sustainable agriculture policy development, governance an
  Mass media; Democracy; Sustainable agriculture; Electronic information resources; Conservation of natural resources; Central American Association de Campesino Organizations for Cooperation and Development; FLACSO (Organization); University of New Mexico; Organization for Tropical Studies; Central American Economic Integration Secretariat; Overseas Development Council
- Program officer recruitment handbook (New York version), Mar. (Reports 013566), 1999 (Box 718, Reel R-9295)
  Handbook is designed to be a resource for directors, representatives and other involved with program officer recruitment [and aims to] document good practice and to encourage new and improved practices (Introduction, page 1).
  Employees -- Recruiting; Office procedures; Ford Foundation. Office of Human Resources
- Ford Foundation experiments in regional environment management: A symposium of the American Association for the Advancement of Science. (Reports 013567), 1974 (Box 718, Reel R-9295)
  Environmental policy -- United States; Regional planning -- United States; American Association for the Advancement of Science
- Asset building and community development program: FY 1997 program budget review, Dec. 23 (Reports 013568), 1996-1997 (Box 718, Reel R-9295)
  Program budgets for FY 1997 for the community development program, office of the vice president, human development and reproductive health, and economic development.
  Office management; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Finance; Ford Foundation. Asset Building and Community Development
- Learning from Islam: Advocacy of reproductive rights in Indonesian pesantren, Nov. 1996 published (Reports 013569) (Box 718, Reel R-9295)
  Paper focuses on the innovative approach of the Indonesian Society for Pesantren and Community Development to understanding women's rights in relation to reproductive and sexual health in the Indonesian socio-cultural context (Abstract, page 86).
  Sex -- Religious aspects -- Islam; Reproductive health -- Indonesia; Birth control -- Indonesia; Women's rights -- Indonesia; Sex discrimination against women -- Indonesia; Public health -- Indonesia; Sexual ethics -- Indonesia; AIDS (Disease) -- Indonesia; Perhimpunan Pengembangan Pesantren dan Masyarakat (Jakarta, Indonesia); Ford Foundation. Human Rights and Governance
- Proposed FY '98, FY '99 Field Office program budgets: draft 1998? (Reports 013570) (Box 718, Reel R-9295)